<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NEO360Africa Financial Blog.</title>
    <description>NEO360Africa Financial Blog.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 04:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 04:00:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What successful entrepreneurs have to say about business</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Being an entrepreneur could be quite overwhelming. You try, you fail, you run, you fall. It could be a challenge and the motivation probably is not out there. 20 motivational quotes have been provided to keep you going and see you through the tough phase of your journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. “Business opportunities are like buses: there’s always another one coming.” &lt;em&gt;-Richard Branson, Chairman and Founder of Virgin Group&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. A lot of people have ideas, but there are few who decide to do something about them now. Not tomorrow. Not next week. But today. The true entrepreneur is a doer, not a dreamer.” &lt;em&gt;-Nolan Bushnell, Entrepreneur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. “If Plan A doesn’t work, the alphabet has 25 more letters.” &lt;em&gt;-Claire Cook, Author&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. “Don’t limit yourself. Many people limit themselves to what they think they can do. You can go as far as your mind lets you. What you believe, remember you can achieve.” &lt;em&gt;-Mary Kay Ash, Mary Kay Cosmetics Founder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. “The secret of getting ahead is getting started. The secret of getting started is breaking your complex overwhelming tasks into smaller manageable tasks, and then starting on the first one.” &lt;em&gt;-Mark Twain, American Humorist and Author&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6. “When you find an idea that you just can’t stop thinking about, that’s probably a good one to pursue.” &lt;em&gt;-Josh James, Omniture CEO and Co-Founder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7. “Waiting for perfect is never as smart as making progress.” &lt;em&gt;-Seth Godin, Author&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8. “You must be very patient, very persistent. The world isn’t going to shower gold coins on you just because you have a good idea. You’re going to have to work like crazy to bring that idea to the attention of people. They’re not going to buy it unless they know about it.” &lt;em&gt;-Herb Kelleher, Founder of Southwest Airlines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9. “The price of success is hard work, dedication to the job at hand, and the determination that whether we win or lose, we have applied the best of ourselves to the task at hand.” &lt;em&gt;-Vince Lombardi, Executive, Head coach, Player NFL&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10. “Chase the vision, not the money; the money will end up following you.” &lt;em&gt;-Tony Hsieh, Zappos CEO&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11. “It’s not about money or connections. It’s the willingness to outwork and outlearn everyone when it comes to your business. And if it fails, you learn from what happened and do a better job next time.” &lt;em&gt;-Mark Cuban, Entrepreneur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12. “Great ideas often receive violent opposition from mediocre minds.” &lt;em&gt;-Albert Einstein&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13. “There are no secrets to success. It is the result of preparation, hard work, and learning from failure.” &lt;em&gt;-Colin Powell, U.S. General&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14. “What good is an idea if it remains an idea? Try. Experiment. Iterate. Fail. Try again. Change the world.” &lt;em&gt;-Simon Sinek, Author&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15. “The most valuable thing you can make is a mistake – you can’t learn anything from being perfect.” &lt;em&gt;-Adam Osborne&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16. “Don’t wait for perfection. Life isn’t perfect. Do the best you can and ship. Real people ship, and then they test and then they ship again. Then you wake up one day and you have something insanely great.” &lt;em&gt;-Guy Kawasaki, Entrepreneur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17. “Don’t worry about being successful, but work toward being significant and the success will naturally follow.” &lt;em&gt;-Oprah Winfrey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18. “If you know too much before the start, then you will get overwhelmed. Come up with an original idea, and don’t copy because there will be no passion. You need that otherworldly passion. Just start.” &lt;em&gt;-Jeni Britton Bauer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19. “You have to see failure as the beginning and the middle, but never entertain it as an end.” *-Jessica Herrin, Stella &amp;amp; Dot Founder and CEO *&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20. “Nobody talks about entrepreneurship as survival, but that’s exactly what it is and what nurtures creative thinking.”** **&lt;em&gt;-Anita Roddick, The Body Shop Founder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 12:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/motivational-quotes-to-keep-you-going/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/motivational-quotes-to-keep-you-going/</guid>
        
        <category>motivation</category>
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
        <category>inspiration</category>
        
        
        <category>Motivation</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A large number of SMEs can’t afford to fund their growth</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;SMEs create 2 out of every 3 new jobs! Despite this, they are often overlooked and underserved. Small and Medium Scale Enterprises are responsible for the development of new products and services which keeps the economy going. Due to its dynamic nature, SMEs are prone to a high mortality rate caused by sudden shifts in economic policies amongst other factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to research, more than half of SMEs are unable to fund their business ambitions. While there might be an increase in revenue, some find it difficult to reach their business goals. Some of these goals include employing more staff, opening other branches, launching new products and more. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/15-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15-01.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, challenges faced by SMEs include lack of access to affordable finance, skilled workforce, multiplicity of taxes, high cost of doing business, huge gaps in infrastructure and more. Some SMEs were able to share the challenges they face. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I own a small shop in Yaba where I sell clothes and business has been good. I make an average of 150 to 300 thousand naira per month and would love to open another shop in Lagos market, but the responsibilities are too much. I am a widow and have to send my two children to school, I also have to pay rent, in fact, I still take care of my late husband’s mother. I thank God things have been good, but I really wish to open another shop.” &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I started a laundry business in 2017 where I wash, iron and mend clothes for people. I want to grow bigger than this, but not many people are interested in what I’m doing. Some people think it’s just to wash and iron, but it’s more than that and takes a lot of skill. Because of the lack of interest, I’ve also lost employees. Some end up damaging the clothes, while others run away with them to sell. Another issue is power. They don’t provide us with enough electricity, so I have a backup generator. The cost of maintaining the generator and servicing it is not easy. I also have to buy fuel regularly. If all these costs were not there, I believe I would have gone far by now.” &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without the necessary funds and facilities to grow, the economy will remain stagnant and entrepreneurs will lose their businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NEO360 Africa is building the best way to finance your business growth, in a couple of days, our mobile application will be available on google play store.
We implore you to get your businesses ready for NEO360 Africa by registering with the Corporate Affairs Commission and opening a business bank account.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 12:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/sme-owners-cant-bear-to-subsidize-their-development-heres-why/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/sme-owners-cant-bear-to-subsidize-their-development-heres-why/</guid>
        
        <category>entrepreneurs</category>
        
        <category>SMEs</category>
        
        <category>growth</category>
        
        
        <category>Managing Business</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>All work and no play?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You went to work on Monday, visited a client on Tuesday, went to the market on Wednesday, went to work on Thursday, thank God it’s Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/weekend.gif&quot; alt=&quot;weekend.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you doing this weekend? Attending a wedding? Sleeping in? Or one of your customers just called and asked for an impromptu job? Or maybe your employees are misbehaving?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an entrepreneur is not all about work. You should take some time to unwind and have fun. Despite all the motivational quotes that say “work now, play later” or “I don’t take breaks”, it is important that you do take a break. Such would be good for your health. Whilst trying to satisfy your clients, you also should be satisfied. Enjoy yourself, take a break. Relax! If you don’t know how to, here is a list of fun things to do in Lagos for the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go to the cinema (Or stay at home and chill with Netflix)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s like nobody even has time for television these days, you get home and you’re on your phone… chatting, scrolling through pictures or just watching random videos on Twitter. You can’t even sit for a few minutes to check out the news on TV. Your major news provider is probably Instablog or Pulse. It’s understandable. Why don’t you drop the phone for a while and visit the cinema? If you don’t want to, chill at home with Netflix and enjoy one or two movies. It’s just an hour or two (make sure you switch off your phone, so you have rest of mind). You will feel better after. Ensure it’s a genre you like, it could be comedy, romance or Sci-Fi… whatever it is that will entertain you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go to the beach&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/suntan-beach-XCI37iEO8yFpZCTV0nUCnhAUfv1ALG1nLJ3g7fet.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;suntan-beach-XCI37iEO8yFpZCTV0nUCnhAUfv1ALG1nLJ3g7fet.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lagos is full of beaches. There is Elegushi Beach, Tarkwa Bay Beach, Oniru Beach, La Campagne Tropicana Beach Resort, Coconut Beach and many more. These beaches and resorts have perfect views and come with other fun packages such as sports facilities, fine dining, lounges, games and many more. It is an opportunity to take a break from the business world and focus on yourself, friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appreciate art and beauty at the Nike Art Gallery&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/4202980259_04248bdd3b_z-e1439391216462-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4202980259_04248bdd3b_z-e1439391216462-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nike Art Gallery is filled with over a thousand works of art of different genres, ranging from textiles to bead work. Don’t go there just to view the art, but appreciate it. Remember that the artists are entrepreneurs like yourself. Entrance is free and if you appreciate the art enough to buy something, there is a gift shop available in the gallery. Why not support a fellow entrepreneur?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go paintballing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are your employees finding it difficult to work with themselves? Take them paintballing. They will learn by force. Paintballing is an activity that involves shooting people on the opposite team with a fake gun filled with pellets of paint. If you’re too serious at work, it sure would bring out your fun side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go to the Lekki Conservation Centre&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/lekki-conservation-centre-OPARABOY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;lekki-conservation-centre-OPARABOY.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you live in Lagos and you haven’t been here, do you really live in Lagos? And you call yourself a Lagosian… okay, work never allowed you. Well, why not take a break and visit the Lekki Conservation Centre? It is one of the top nature reserves in Nigeria with calm scenery. It is also very popular for having the longest canopy walk in Africa. LCC is definitely one of the top places to unwind and let go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, dear entrepreneurs, how would you be spending your weekend? Other fun and enlightening activities coming soon include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Lagos Digital Marketing Training – October 12th 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Africa Oil &amp;amp; Gas Talent Summit 2019 – October 30th 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;· Lagos Expo 2019: Fashion – November 30th 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HAVE FUN!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 10:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/all-work-and-no-play/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/all-work-and-no-play/</guid>
        
        <category>fun</category>
        
        <category>entertainment</category>
        
        <category>weekend vibes</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Effective ways to handle negative criticism</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The customer is always right.&lt;/em&gt; Is this true? It can be quite tough for entrepreneurs when they put in a lot of effort into a product and are not appreciated for it. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Sean Harper, co-founder of Kin Insurance says, “Feedback is useful. Once I started thinking this way, it made me realize I’m grateful for the opportunity to see an experience from another point of view and hopefully improve.”
Not many people know how to take such feedback. Here are a few things to do when faced with an angry customer: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;understand-the-problem&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understand the problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;giphy.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to understand the problem, one should keep quiet, listen and reflect on what they’ve been told. Understanding the problem would enable you proffer a valuable solution to it. This would prevent more problems and enable customer satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apologise&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apologise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/sorry.gif&quot; alt=&quot;sorry.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you agree with the customer or not, an apology should be given. This shows that you care and are interested in the customer’s opinions. After rendering the apology, engage them in conversation to know what can be done to serve them better. However, do not over apologise and feel too guilty, some people may take that for granted and try to belittle you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-not-let-your-emotions-kick-in&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not let your emotions kick in&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Negative feedback should not be taken too personal. Embrace criticism and use it as an opportunity to improve on your business. Learn from your mistakes and move on. Learn from Mauricio Cardenal who says;
“One of the most profound lessons I’ve learned in my life is that we should not take things too personally. Yes, negative feedback is painful sometimes, but I know that my actions aren’t a reflection of me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;identify-the-cause-of-the-problem&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify the cause of the problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/shane-aldendorff-mQHEgroKw2k-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;shane-aldendorff-mQHEgroKw2k-unsplash.jpg&quot; /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identifying the cause of the problem is one of the first steps to take in order to avoid negative feedback another time. If a customer wasn’t satisfied with the product or service provided, try to identify what went wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;see-it-as-an-opportunity-to-improve&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See it as an opportunity to improve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/progress.gif&quot; alt=&quot;progress.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not everyone is open to criticism and negative feedback, some use it as an opportunity to improve. This leads to increased performance and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/effective-methods-to-handle-negative-criticism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/effective-methods-to-handle-negative-criticism/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Managing Business</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Key factors to consider before business expansion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Business expansion is sometimes critical for increased market share or even survival, however, if not done properly could lead to the downfall of the business. At the same time if done too early, it could result in the business crumbling and if done too late, could result in losing market share and relevance. &lt;br /&gt;
To be frank, expansion isn’t just about more revenues. You want to think &lt;strong&gt;sustainability&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;wider reach&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;business development&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;innovation&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and of course&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;more money&lt;/strong&gt;. Expansion is really all encompassing. So how do you know if your small business is ready for expansion?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;structure-systems-and-processes&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structure, Systems and Processes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Building-Blocks.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Building-Blocks.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is your business rightly structured to manage the diversity that comes with growth? Do you have processes within your business to ensure quality across board and maintenance of your core values? Will your business shred apart when you go for a 3 months vacation? If you answered in the negative, then your business isn’t ready for growth. It doesn’t really matter how much you are making in revenue and profits if your business revolves around you. If you do not institute structure, processes and systems in your business, test them for a while before expanding, then you may cause problems for your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;human-capacity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Human Capacity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Business-36-24ddad.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Business-36-24ddad.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have the requisite manpower to manage the additional demands that accompany expansion? What is the composition of your team in terms of expertise, skills and intellectual range? &lt;br /&gt;
If you cannot confidently beat your chest in response to these questions, then you have to hold off expansion until you have the right people on your team and they are well trained to handle the pressure of expansion. On the other hand, if your business is hard pressed to expand and you don’t have the required capital, you can get financing to hire additional staff then proceed to expand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cash-flow&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cash Flow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Illustrator-03-4cf572.png&quot; alt=&quot;Illustrator-03-4cf572.png&quot; /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cash flow is inherently different from generating sales revenues. If after deducting your production costs, variable costs and there is barely any reasonable profit commensurate to the effort, resources and time put into the production and sales cycle or the profit can barely even cover marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scalability&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your business is really growing, then you should not have to spend so much more to increase your revenue base. This means if you spend ₦250,000 to produce 1000 units of a product (which translates into ₦250 per 1 unit of product), then you should not be spending beyond ₦350,000 to produce 1500 units. With economies of scale, increased revenues should not cost more to deliver than current revenues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;customer-segment&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer Segment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This involves having an increased demand for your product or services and also diversifying your revenue sources. When you have an increased demand for your products, then you want to start thinking about expansion. However, you have to first ensure that your team can meet up with production and after sales services. On the other hand, if 40% of your revenue comes from a particular client, especially for B2B businesses, then you might have to expand your business to acquire more customers. The danger of having 40% of your revenue from one source is not sustainable in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;market-analysis&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Analytics-Concept-Finance-Infographic-AurielAki-c18c60.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Analytics-Concept-Finance-Infographic-AurielAki-c18c60.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t just wake up one morning and decide to expand your business from Lagos to Abuja or from Nigeria to London without taking the time to analyse the new market. Apart from regulatory requirements, customers in this region are probably meeting their needs with available products or close substitutes. More so, they have certain preferences that might be a tad different from that of your current customer base. So, you need to carry out a comprehensive market analysis to ascertain if your business can thrive in the intended market or if you need some iteration of your product or marketing strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Does your business tick all these boxes but lack the needed finance for expansion? Or you still need some clarity on how to go about your expansion? Get low interest financing from NEO360 or speak to one of our business advisors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 08:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/key-factors-to-consider-before-business-expansion/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/key-factors-to-consider-before-business-expansion/</guid>
        
        <category>business</category>
        
        <category>expansion</category>
        
        <category>growth</category>
        
        <category>entrepreneur</category>
        
        
        <category>Managing Business</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor. If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/powerful-things-markdown-editor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/powerful-things-markdown-editor/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/first-mass-produced/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/first-mass-produced/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Education must also train one for quick, resolute and effective thinking.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Rouge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/education/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/education/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accumulated experience of social living</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/acumulated-experience/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/acumulated-experience/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>About Bundler</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gem install bundler&lt;/code&gt; installs the bundler gem through RubyGems. You only need to install it once - not every time you create a new Jekyll project. Here are some additional details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundler&lt;/code&gt; is a gem that manages other Ruby gems. It makes sure your gems and gem versions are compatible, and that you have all necessary dependencies each gem requires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/code&gt; files inform &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/code&gt; about the gem requirements in your site. If your site doesn’t have these Gemfiles, you can omit &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec&lt;/code&gt; and just &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;run jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/code&gt; uses the gems and versions as specified in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Gemfile.lock&lt;/code&gt; to ensure your Jekyll site builds with no compatibility or dependency conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about how to use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/code&gt; in your Jekyll project, this tutorial should provide answers to the most common questions and explain how to get up and running quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/about-bundler/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/about-bundler/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
